Guide to the Robert B. McKersie Collections 1965-2017
McKersie, Robert B. Collections
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Robert B. McKersie Collections, 1965-2017
/4343
McKersie, Robert B.; Brookings Institution; Slichter, Sumner H.; Healy, James J.; Livernash, E. Robert; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
0 linear ft.
Records (documents), papers (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
This consists of links to Robert B. McKersie's collections.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert B. McKersie, DBA
Professor of Management, Emeritus, Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
Robert McKersie is professor emeritus of management at the MIT Sloan School of Management, where he has been since 1980. Prior to his time at MIT, he served as dean of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, and as a faculty member of the Graduate School of Business at the University of Chicago. McKersie has served on several presidential commissions at the national level, is a member of the National Academy of Arbitrators, and was president of the National Industrial Relations Research Association (now the Labor and Employment Relations Association). He is the author of numerous articles relating to human resources, industrial relations, and operations management.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McKersie, Robert B.; Slichter, Sumner H. (Sumner Huber), 1892-1959; Healy, James J.; Livernash, E. Robert (Edward Robert); Brookings Institution; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.; Ryder/P. I. E. Nationwide Trucking Company
Subjects:
Collective bargaining
Geographic Subjects:
Nassau County (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents); Papers (documents).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
/4343: Robert B. McKersie Collections
/4054: ILR School Dean's Office Additional Files
/4064: Kurt Hanslowe Papers
/4073: James O. Morris Office Files
/4083: ILR School Alumni Association Files
/4142: Robert B. McKersie Additional Papers
6118 AV: Kheel Center AV Collection
/4054: ILR School Dean's Office Additional Files
5464: U.S. Economic Stabilization Program Records
CONTAINER LIST
- /4033: Robert B. McKersie Files, 1965-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  7 linear feet
- /4071: Robert B. McKersie Additional Files, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  4 linear feet
- /4142: Robert B. McKersie Additional Papers, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  1 linear foot
- /4284: Robert B. McKersie Additional Papers (Box 1, Folder 4)
  3 linear feet
- 6213: Robert B. McKersie Additional Files (Box 1, Folder 5)
  10 linear feet
- 6325: Robert B. McKersie PIE Trucking Company Files, 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 6326: Robert B. McKersie Research Collection for "The Impact of Collective Bargaining on Management", 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 6327: Robert B. McKersie Nassau County Multi-Municipality Productivity Project Files, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 6958: Robert B. McKersie Arbitration, Civil Rights, and Interrogation Files (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 6958 AV: Robert B. McKersie Arbitration, Civil Rights, and Interrogation Audio-Visual Materials (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 6967 AV(d): Robert B. McKersie Remarks at the Kheel Center, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 11)